<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-29T12:31:44+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">The Inquisitive Mortal</title><subtitle>I am Hitesh Gautam and this is my journey</subtitle><author><name>Hitesh Gautam</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Reboot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/28/the-reboot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Reboot" /><published>2018-08-28T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/28/the-reboot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/28/the-reboot.html">&lt;p&gt;Almost two months since the last post and so much has changed (in terms of perception). The weather of Bangalore, people, news and many such things show so subtle change that they look the same but a lot seems to have changed underneath. It’s like an abstraction layer making us to move forward, like the time making us to follow it, whereever it is leading us to.
Coming to simpler things travelling without planning is fun. From being a over prepared to the most non-ready person on the planet, feels like quite a journey. For example, I am used to carry all kinds of denominations of currency so I never need to slow myself down for some trasaction process we created (we could have been exchanging goods in good faith and having fun), but this time I had no cash and some random fellow passenger paid for me. I couldn’t even ask his name, but for that humble anonymous I will carry cash always and pay for any person who is ready to dive into the world of travlling without thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hitesh Gautam ***</name></author><summary type="html">Almost two months since the last post and so much has changed (in terms of perception). The weather of Bangalore, people, news and many such things show so subtle change that they look the same but a lot seems to have changed underneath. It’s like an abstraction layer making us to move forward, like the time making us to follow it, whereever it is leading us to. Coming to simpler things travelling without planning is fun. From being a over prepared to the most non-ready person on the planet, feels like quite a journey. For example, I am used to carry all kinds of denominations of currency so I never need to slow myself down for some trasaction process we created (we could have been exchanging goods in good faith and having fun), but this time I had no cash and some random fellow passenger paid for me. I couldn’t even ask his name, but for that humble anonymous I will carry cash always and pay for any person who is ready to dive into the world of travlling without thinking.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The ledge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/07/01/the-ledge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The ledge" /><published>2018-07-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/07/01/the-ledge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/07/01/the-ledge.html">&lt;p&gt;So, realized that the bucket list I created for a week was a little bit unrealistic. It could have worked if I was aiming it for 100% of my time and if this was the case I would never had found out how honey bees decide their queen and that there is Movidius USB stick for Deep Learning.
So, I guess while climbing mountains one definitely goes for the safest and tried way but if it comes to being an expert at that or when surviving is not a one-dimensional data but rather a sub node of so many other sub nodes (like in a graph where one node is surrounded by choices, which are surrounded by feedbacks or emotional parameters) he/she needs to break the loop and try something different. But the point of confusion is whether to hold on to the current ledge or leap to a better one by taking risk of loosing the already covered distance. Is experience an answer of that? If yes, then how to make experience function less dependent on the time variable.
May be one day we will be able to visualize our whole life into a single Neural Network and then figure out whether the ones with higher connectivity (conventional paths) made more sense or the linear ones (more experiments, more risks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, I think I need to learn to put things into the simplest possible way and I need a validator for this (experience?).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hitesh Gautam ****</name></author><summary type="html">So, realized that the bucket list I created for a week was a little bit unrealistic. It could have worked if I was aiming it for 100% of my time and if this was the case I would never had found out how honey bees decide their queen and that there is Movidius USB stick for Deep Learning. So, I guess while climbing mountains one definitely goes for the safest and tried way but if it comes to being an expert at that or when surviving is not a one-dimensional data but rather a sub node of so many other sub nodes (like in a graph where one node is surrounded by choices, which are surrounded by feedbacks or emotional parameters) he/she needs to break the loop and try something different. But the point of confusion is whether to hold on to the current ledge or leap to a better one by taking risk of loosing the already covered distance. Is experience an answer of that? If yes, then how to make experience function less dependent on the time variable. May be one day we will be able to visualize our whole life into a single Neural Network and then figure out whether the ones with higher connectivity (conventional paths) made more sense or the linear ones (more experiments, more risks).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Present</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/28/the-present.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Present" /><published>2018-06-28T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-06-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/28/the-present</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/28/the-present.html">&lt;p&gt;I usually find myself in phases, defined by recurrence of something (can be an experience, smell, feeling or even an actor appearing in the movies that you find yourself seeing, everyday in my case). These phases seem to focussing on something that eventually I put into my “Archive”. These days life has been giving emphasis on the word “Present”. Whether it is Instagram, series I am currently watching : “This is us”, or a scolding from mom (on acting lazy), I found myself appreciating the current moment. I have used different threads over past, present and future but now, I am trying to devise a way to focus on the present and have dedicated time for retrospection and planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will continue on this later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note to self: Add section for movies, series with reviews.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hitesh Gautam ****</name></author><summary type="html">I usually find myself in phases, defined by recurrence of something (can be an experience, smell, feeling or even an actor appearing in the movies that you find yourself seeing, everyday in my case). These phases seem to focussing on something that eventually I put into my “Archive”. These days life has been giving emphasis on the word “Present”. Whether it is Instagram, series I am currently watching : “This is us”, or a scolding from mom (on acting lazy), I found myself appreciating the current moment. I have used different threads over past, present and future but now, I am trying to devise a way to focus on the present and have dedicated time for retrospection and planning.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The begining</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/27/the-begining.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The begining" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/27/the-begining</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/27/the-begining.html">&lt;p&gt;This is the most promising start for my blog in years. Posted twice in blogspot, 5 times in wordpress, but I was never satisfied with them. Big thumbs up to the guy who introduced this idea in my life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We don’t need motivation, we just need a fu@#ing reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That illuminated the significance of discipline, perseverance. I will try to post things up so that the required transformation comes quicker or I am able to make continuous progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to add the following things into my blog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;task-list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Bucket list (weekly)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;Thought of the day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Blog&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;Technical Notes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;CV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Movies List&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;TV Series List&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hitesh Gautam **</name></author><summary type="html">This is the most promising start for my blog in years. Posted twice in blogspot, 5 times in wordpress, but I was never satisfied with them. Big thumbs up to the guy who introduced this idea in my life: We don’t need motivation, we just need a fu@#ing reason.</summary></entry></feed>