<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-09T16:58:34+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">The Inquisitive Mortal</title><subtitle>I am Hitesh Gautam and this is my journey</subtitle><author><name>Hitesh Gautam</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Disagreement</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/09/the-disagreement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Disagreement" /><published>2019-01-09T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-01-09T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/09/the-disagreement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/09/the-disagreement.html">&lt;p&gt;I don’t agree with many(any) of the practices currently being followed in the whole world.
From lying (I get surprised when people justify this) to not giving your full, from cheating to getting more (than required) profit (this is also hypothetical), everything makes me feel uncomfortable. I used to think that not lying or not manipulating should be the default case scenario. Communication is the ladder that made us evolve from other primates and we have made that ladder a web. Imagine this, if there were no lies or in abstract terms ‘No bad data’, everything could have made sense, everything would have helped in our growth. 
&lt;strong&gt;But if I correlate capitalism here then everyone has the right to be at his/her max. comfort and to be there you have the right to do anything.&lt;/strong&gt;
And I am being told that emotions are for pussies (cats -_-).
So, my level of emotional intelligence is not going to do any good and rather would harm me if I am surrounded by Predators (?). 
Or my disagreement lies with the lack of understanding of EQ, people, society, life. 
But this feeling of confusion and yearn to understand why everything is happening the way it is, does open new doors (which could have been locked forever).
In short:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Consume information and be at a level (where you have principles, understanding etc.) from where you can identify where to question and where to stop following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The way this world is right now (considering it the best case scenario among all the permutations that could have left it in the worst state), everyone can follow whatever they want to (even create followers of your own). This is an interesting time we are living in, predictable but still surprising us on every turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ps-abstract-thought&quot;&gt;P.S: (Abstract thought):&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider electrons as followers and nucleus as a leader (with the chain of protons (leaders) over a period of time). Followers surrounding the leader, who dared to accumulate knowledge over time and made his/her own element. And BTW are we done with the periodic table? No more elements to discover or create?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hitesh Gautam * *</name></author><summary type="html">I don’t agree with many(any) of the practices currently being followed in the whole world. From lying (I get surprised when people justify this) to not giving your full, from cheating to getting more (than required) profit (this is also hypothetical), everything makes me feel uncomfortable. I used to think that not lying or not manipulating should be the default case scenario. Communication is the ladder that made us evolve from other primates and we have made that ladder a web. Imagine this, if there were no lies or in abstract terms ‘No bad data’, everything could have made sense, everything would have helped in our growth. But if I correlate capitalism here then everyone has the right to be at his/her max. comfort and to be there you have the right to do anything. And I am being told that emotions are for pussies (cats -_-). So, my level of emotional intelligence is not going to do any good and rather would harm me if I am surrounded by Predators (?). Or my disagreement lies with the lack of understanding of EQ, people, society, life. But this feeling of confusion and yearn to understand why everything is happening the way it is, does open new doors (which could have been locked forever). In short: Consume information and be at a level (where you have principles, understanding etc.) from where you can identify where to question and where to stop following.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Intermission</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/31/the-intermission.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Intermission" /><published>2018-12-31T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-12-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/31/the-intermission</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/31/the-intermission.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Last day of the year!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another year passed away.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resolutions!!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year I started making a list of things I wanted to do. When I reached at item 32, it seemed redundant. Learning languages, tech stacks, create DIY projects and what not, the list had different items but the all the things seemed to be converging at a point. I paused and decided to complete these first and then write the rest later.
Took quite a time to realize all those things were a child of expectations (from people and from myself) which I seem to magnify quite a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;e.g. A IoT switch can be implemented on a bread-board, using led and a NodeMCU chip. But instead of a simple POC, I went and bought NeoPixels 5050 strip (thrice), Arduino, NodeMCU. (It’s like upgrading to cheesy fries and float from a normal meal at MC Donalds.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result was beautiful but the purpose got lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Isn’t the same thing is happening everywhere?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;new-year-resolutions-coming-up&quot;&gt;New Year Resolutions coming up.&lt;/h1&gt;</content><author><name>Hitesh Gautam *</name></author><summary type="html">Last day of the year! Another year passed away. Resolutions!!!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Accessory</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/20/the-accessory.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Accessory" /><published>2018-12-20T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-12-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/20/the-accessory</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/20/the-accessory.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Enjoy simple things in life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some quotes whose origin seem to be untraceable but I feel obligated to follow them. Now, I am feeling forced to list down all such quotes/phrases which I am following unconsciously, but they do direct a part of my life. (I will do this in my next post and might add some lessons associated with them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do like sipping tea while watching sunset/sunrise. Though the wires and the buildings do mess up the scene sometimes but still they can’t spoil the most beautiful part of the day (A long breath and the scene does its magic anywhere).
Yes, watching it from a balcony of a five-star, on the deck of the ship in the middle of the ocean, amongst the hills with clouds or just driving down a road, each has its own experience ( All of them can be symbolised as career choices or summed up effect of life’s tests ), but running after an accessory wasn’t taught to me.
A lot of beliefs have been shattered and rebuilt in the recent past and this is a good sign, a sign of life and the change driving it forward. I still don’t know whether to focus on the serenity that the &lt;strong&gt;Belt of the Venus&lt;/strong&gt; is giving me or to run after the accessories that might open a stimulus that I am not aware of. 
But this cycle of &lt;strong&gt;Ending&lt;/strong&gt; and new &lt;strong&gt;Beginning&lt;/strong&gt; will mesmerize whoever pauses and accepts the extent of time and universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Till I/We figure it out, let’s cherish what we have got today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hitesh Gautam *</name></author><summary type="html">Enjoy simple things in life</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Reboot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/28/the-reboot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Reboot" /><published>2018-08-28T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-08-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/28/the-reboot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/28/the-reboot.html">&lt;p&gt;Almost two months since the last post and so much has changed (in terms of perception). The weather of Bangalore, people, news and many such things show so subtle change that they look the same but a lot seems to have changed underneath. It’s like an abstraction layer, making us to move forward, like the time making us to follow it, where ever it is leading us to.
Coming to simpler things traveling without planning is fun. From being an over prepared to be the most non-ready person on the planet, feels like quite a journey. For example, I am used to carry all kinds of denominations of currency so I never need to slow myself down for some transaction process we created (we could have been exchanging goods in good faith and having fun), but this time I had no cash and some random fellow passenger paid for me. I couldn’t even ask his name, but for that humble anonymous I will carry cash always and pay for any person who is ready to dive into the world of traveling without thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hitesh Gautam ***</name></author><summary type="html">Almost two months since the last post and so much has changed (in terms of perception). The weather of Bangalore, people, news and many such things show so subtle change that they look the same but a lot seems to have changed underneath. It’s like an abstraction layer, making us to move forward, like the time making us to follow it, where ever it is leading us to. Coming to simpler things traveling without planning is fun. From being an over prepared to be the most non-ready person on the planet, feels like quite a journey. For example, I am used to carry all kinds of denominations of currency so I never need to slow myself down for some transaction process we created (we could have been exchanging goods in good faith and having fun), but this time I had no cash and some random fellow passenger paid for me. I couldn’t even ask his name, but for that humble anonymous I will carry cash always and pay for any person who is ready to dive into the world of traveling without thinking.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The ledge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/07/01/the-ledge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The ledge" /><published>2018-07-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/07/01/the-ledge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/07/01/the-ledge.html">&lt;p&gt;So, realized that the bucket list I created for a week was a little bit unrealistic. It could have worked if I was aiming it for 100% of my time and if this was the case I would never had found out how honey bees decide their queen and that there is Movidius USB stick for Deep Learning.
So, I guess while climbing mountains one definitely goes for the safest and tried way but if it comes to being an expert at that or when surviving is not a one-dimensional data but rather a sub node of so many other sub nodes (like in a graph where one node is surrounded by choices, which are surrounded by feedbacks or emotional parameters) he/she needs to break the loop and try something different. But the point of confusion is whether to hold on to the current ledge or leap to a better one by taking risk of loosing the already covered distance. Is experience an answer of that? If yes, then how to make experience function less dependent on the time variable.
May be one day we will be able to visualize our whole life into a single Neural Network and then figure out whether the ones with higher connectivity (conventional paths) made more sense or the linear ones (more experiments, more risks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, I think I need to learn to put things into the simplest possible way and I need a validator for this (experience?).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hitesh Gautam ****</name></author><summary type="html">So, realized that the bucket list I created for a week was a little bit unrealistic. It could have worked if I was aiming it for 100% of my time and if this was the case I would never had found out how honey bees decide their queen and that there is Movidius USB stick for Deep Learning. So, I guess while climbing mountains one definitely goes for the safest and tried way but if it comes to being an expert at that or when surviving is not a one-dimensional data but rather a sub node of so many other sub nodes (like in a graph where one node is surrounded by choices, which are surrounded by feedbacks or emotional parameters) he/she needs to break the loop and try something different. But the point of confusion is whether to hold on to the current ledge or leap to a better one by taking risk of loosing the already covered distance. Is experience an answer of that? If yes, then how to make experience function less dependent on the time variable. May be one day we will be able to visualize our whole life into a single Neural Network and then figure out whether the ones with higher connectivity (conventional paths) made more sense or the linear ones (more experiments, more risks).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Present</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/28/the-present.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Present" /><published>2018-06-28T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-06-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/28/the-present</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/28/the-present.html">&lt;p&gt;I usually find myself in phases, defined by recurrence of something (can be an experience, smell, feeling or even an actor appearing in the movies that you find yourself seeing, everyday in my case). These phases seem to focussing on something that eventually I put into my “Archive”. These days life has been giving emphasis on the word “Present”. Whether it is Instagram, series I am currently watching : “This is us”, or a scolding from mom (on acting lazy), I found myself appreciating the current moment. I have used different threads over past, present and future but now, I am trying to devise a way to focus on the present and have dedicated time for retrospection and planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will continue on this later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note to self: Add section for movies, series with reviews.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hitesh Gautam ****</name></author><summary type="html">I usually find myself in phases, defined by recurrence of something (can be an experience, smell, feeling or even an actor appearing in the movies that you find yourself seeing, everyday in my case). These phases seem to focussing on something that eventually I put into my “Archive”. These days life has been giving emphasis on the word “Present”. Whether it is Instagram, series I am currently watching : “This is us”, or a scolding from mom (on acting lazy), I found myself appreciating the current moment. I have used different threads over past, present and future but now, I am trying to devise a way to focus on the present and have dedicated time for retrospection and planning.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The begining</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/27/the-begining.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The begining" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/27/the-begining</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/27/the-begining.html">&lt;p&gt;This is the most promising start for my blog in years. Posted twice in blogspot, 5 times in wordpress, but I was never satisfied with them. Big thumbs up to the guy who introduced this idea in my life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We don’t need motivation, we just need a fu@#ing reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That illuminated the significance of discipline, perseverance. I will try to post things up so that the required transformation comes quicker or I am able to make continuous progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to add the following things into my blog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;task-list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Bucket list (weekly)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;Thought of the day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Blog&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;Technical Notes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;CV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Movies List&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;TV Series List&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hitesh Gautam **</name></author><summary type="html">This is the most promising start for my blog in years. Posted twice in blogspot, 5 times in wordpress, but I was never satisfied with them. Big thumbs up to the guy who introduced this idea in my life: We don’t need motivation, we just need a fu@#ing reason.</summary></entry></feed>